Where the [ __ ] is all the automation? AI
is so unbelievably smart and yet it's so
useless at all other stuff.
>> It doesn't matter how much AI coding
agents you use, the software actually
isn't getting better. [laughter]
Maybe you're writing it faster. It's
like arguably getting worse.
>> OpenAI has been trying to automate
customer service since 2020. What I want
instead is smart software. I want to
expand what software itself can do such
that things that should be automatable
can then be automatable. My favorite
thing that you guys say is we build prod
not god. So good
>> because if we had any other kind of like
big lab leader even if they had joy they
would cover everything
>> and then your view is so different.
You're like no we're going to create a
way better world
>> for nuanced reasons. I don't think we
are on the path of RSI in the SAS
apocalypse story. [music] Um
today we have the founder and leader of
Typesafe, Diego with us. Um who uh is a
bit of a hero to both Martine and me.
Yes.
>> Um he is not only building like a really
interesting product uh but creating what
we think is a very important movement.
So we're super excited about today.
>> Welcome. Thank you for coming. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. And uh maybe you can give us kind
of a a brief on um just you know what is
Jev? What is type safe? Why is it
important?
>> Is this a curse friendly or no?
>> Okay. [ __ ] are you talking about?
>> Okay. Okay. Okay. Cool. So I was
actually asked for like a elevator pitch
which I tend to ramble on and I don't do
well but like I realized my favorite
elevator pitch for Jev is where the [ __ ]
is all the automation? Like this is like
so unbelievably tragic, you know, so
much intelligence. AI is so unbelievably
smart and yet so not that I hate on chat
bots or coding agents. I love them
myself, but it's like it's so useless at
all other stuff and it's it's tragic.
It's tragic that, you know, we have so
much like diamond in the rough but not
polished for work. That's that's a but
type safe is making AI for software. You
know, we want to make AI powerful not
just for humans in the loop, but to
actually build real software and JIE to
us is our first model in this whole
space to make it way way better to like
make automation.
>> Yeah. And so it's been interesting
because it's kind of caught fire in
software world. So, you know, one of the
things that made us go, "What the hell's
going on here?" is like every developer
we know is calling us and going, "Oh,
this is freaking awesome. It's great.
It's fast. It's it's great. Everything's
better. Um, and h then how does that uh
cuz because everybody thinks of well
we've got cloud code you know we've got
codecs don't we already have that? Like
what's the difference? And then how does
that lead to real automation?
>> Oo I wish I had like a some slopp
visuals because I have like a favorite
sloped visual for this. So I like cloud
code and codeex. Um I love the
description from Gary Tan on them. It's
just in time software, you know,
incredible way to describe what they're
doing. It like it makes software on the
fly and you can like program software in
natural language, but it has the same
expressive power as software.
>> Um, what I want instead is smart
software. Like instead of like
automating software engineering, I want
to expand what software itself can do
such that things that could should be
automatable can then be automatable. and
like in a more um flowery language like
I want to express things like intent. I
want to like expand the vocabulary of
what we can do and I can talk about like
all sorts of like weird sci-fi things I
want but like programming is like hyper
specifying like valuable things and then
infinitely replicating them. It's so
freaking cool and I want to just make
that more, you know?
>> Oh, interesting. So, so one way to think
about it is instead of kind of a tool
that uh
somewhat replaces a software engineer
with a faster, maybe not even as good
software engineer. What you're saying is
no, no, no. We're going to supermpower
the software engineers we have to write
way, way better, more interesting
things.
>> Yeah. I I actually I mean Yeah. Yeah. So
this is by the way I just think so many
people miss this point and it's such a
subtle point and it's so important to
actually tease it out which is um if you
use something like cloud code or codex
which is great or cursor which is great
>> they write code but that code is the
same thing a human being would have
write maybe it's better maybe it's worse
but it's basically still code just like
code looked 10 years ago.
>> Yeah. And and the thing with Jev is
whether or not you're cloud code or a
human, you have this new primitive, this
new thing that you stick in your code
that actually expands like the power of
software. So instead of like writing
code, it is something that you include
in your code
>> which go ahead. Well, which which by the
way is interesting because it's this
very powerful primitive which would be
great if you explain but it's also a
little bit different than like you know
how programmers think. for example like
it has this notion of like you know
probabilities or you know and like so
you know so
>> so an intelligent layer inside the
software.
>> Yeah. Think of like like a li yeah like
a library that you can like use natural
language to describe what you want and
you give it kind of a state machine and
then it will will choose what to do with
some confidence levels which we kind of
haven't really had before like so
ubiquitous. So maybe
>> ooh there's a lot of tricks there. I
will jump into one thing first which is
I love the first thing you said like
>> you know in the direction of where the
[ __ ] is all the all automation. I love
software so much. I wish I could be
writing it all day. It's
>> would not recommend being a CEO to
people but whatever. Um, and also like
it's wild that AI is so cool and
software has been unchanged in 10 years,
you know, like like like that to me like
no one can like square this together and
the most we can do is add like a little
chatbot in the side sometimes that can
take actions but not all actions cuz
some of the actions are not reliable
now. So I just want to give like that
tiny aside. Um,
>> I love the point I'm gonna jump back to
the point about like this is a little
bit of a different way to think about
it. Um yes I think that machine native
doesn't exactly match bits perfectly and
like that's actually the art form that
we are trying to do like I in our
onboarding on day one I draw like the
vin diagram of like what AI is good at
what is valuable in code we are in the
middle so you know we don't output like
you know extrapolated floats for example
cuz like AI is just bad at that you know
but things like probabilities are not
exactly novel And it's similar to the is
Jev just a classifier argument.
>> Jev is absolutely a classifier. You
know, like classifiers are sick.
Classifiers were designed to be useful.
>> Yeah, they're designed to be useful. And
actually, it's the same interface as
like some of those ML concepts because
these came from like practical people
who are trying to make systems work. And
what I'm seeing is happening now is that
Jev actually I my guess is that Jev
probably is better than having like an
MLE team from 2019 making the stuff for
you and you can just program it on the
fly. Who knows what could be built cuz
like there were not that many good ML
team MLE teams in 2019 to build like
narrow things and to be able to like
collect data sets and measure it and all
of that. And it is just the beginning.
There's I feel like there's way like
like by the way to this point do you
think there's a slider bar here where
like on one end is like language in
language out like we have today on the
other end is like a like an existing
imperative program and then you can kind
of move between the two or do you think
like this is like the point in the
design space which is language in kind
of state machine out which is going to
like solidify as a general purpose thing
for programmers.
>> Ooh that's a tricky one. So I will say
the answer in my heart yeah the answer
in my heart is that it is a slider. So
in and actually when I design for our
the properties we have I might have made
mistakes due to my personal preferences
but like intelligence per dollar is my
northstar right now and it could be
wrong just to be clear intelligence per
second might be more valuable in the
short term but like even like our
interface like calling the input state
this is intentional like it's to say
>> oh that's great I didn't catch that
>> it's meant to be the insides of programs
so
>> so in my heart because like so we are
really optimizing a lot of the work I do
is for even more complicated
arrangements of the internals of program
state. Can you put intelligence in
there? I think this is going to be an
everpresent battle to have I, you know,
we're very intentional about our design
and also pragmatically I think certain
things happen like it's easier to make
an AI at these milliseconds. So it'll be
more like a database for a while than
like a standard library thing. But I
would love it to be a standard library
thing too.
>> Can I can I just pull back like what is
the alchemy that creates a do yogo? I
mean like you speak when a man
[laughter] and a woman love each other
but like listen you speak like an AI
researcher you speak speak like a
systems person you speak like a
programmer and normally these things
have been like not super overlapping and
like you're you're taking you know AI
which we've been pushing towards you
know being a being and you're making it
a programmer's tool. So maybe a little
bit about your personal journey that
>> my history into AI is somewhat
unorthodox. Um, I was a mathlete. Um, I
was a award-winning mathlete. Um, the
way I describe it is I was good enough
at This is cringe. I was good enough at
math to get girls. So, that's quite
good.
>> No, that was a thing.
>> YEAH, YOU HAVE TO get you have to get
quite good. Um,
>> and what kind of girls do you get when
you're that good at math? That's an
>> Oh, that's our audience needs to know.
>> Oh, no.
>> We have to inspire the youth here.
[laughter]
>> Don't do it. Youth, don't do it. It's
not worth it. Just be cool and chill and
interesting and
>> don't overcompensate.
>> Wow, I can't believe I said that. Um,
[laughter]
>> so I was a math athlete,
>> but I actually never Oh man, this also
is a little cringe. I never really liked
math. I never really tried. I was just
like big fish in little pond. And to me,
math was act I math was always the path
I was set on, but I hated it because it
was always about like winning
competitions. But then computer science
is actually a lot like math. It's
basically like math but cool and useful
and fun and interesting and I still love
giving algorithms interviews. It's the
best thing for me to do. I don't know.
But do I love it? Yes. And does it like
allow me to like sus people out really
well? Yes, it does. So I love computer
science. I consider myself to be
computer scientist much more before AI
researcher despite my history. And um
like what actually got me into it was I
also won a kegle competition not from
sophisticated math but from like just
automating like the [ __ ] out of it.
[clears throat] Um
>> you know like just like more nested
loops more you know like I solved it
like a systems problem you know. So that
eventually got me um like I was forced
to speak at Nurups normally an honor but
I hated it cuz I just wanted to be in
the mines.
>> Was that from the Kaggle team?
>> Yes.
>> Oh wow. Yeah, actually the Kaggle host
of it was Isabel Guong who was the
co-inventor of the SVM. Actually, I
think the first author of SVM. I'm not
100% sure first author. Um, and she just
basically saw that I was like this
person who really didn't fit into the
research community and then adopted me
and showed me like like it got me to
meet all the AI people and that you know
my career was just pushed into that
direction.
>> And from there open AI? No, it was like
a startup with Jeremy Howard. Um,
>> no kidding. Yes, I love Jeremy.
Fantastic.
>> Cool.
>> Um, and then Google Brain for a while.
>> Wow.
>> And then, uh, retire for a while.
>> And then eventually I was like just kind
of tired of not doing anything. I was
like, you know what? Actually, AI is
pretty damn fun. And I joined OpenAI
because of that reason. Uh, and it
worked out really well.
>> Amazing.
>> Really, really well.
>> Yeah. Incredible. So, you you said
something there that is so um unusual in
today's world, which is AI is really,
really fun. And then the company has
such a different demeanor and view of AI
than every everybody else. And my
favorite thing that you guys say is we
build prod not god. So good. Because if
we had any other kind of like big lab
leader, they'd be like trying to even if
they had joy, they would cover
[laughter]
and then your view is so different.
You're like, "No, we're going to create
a way better world and it's going to be
awesome and there's going to be not only
are there not going to be less jobs,
there'll be more jobs and there'll be
way better jobs and everybody's going to
have a great time and like just be being
around you like you clearly believe
that." So, so tell us about that and
like what this because for us, you know,
type safe Jev, it's it's more than a
company. It's a it's a whole movement
towards a positive future that most
people in the AI world kind of don't
like.
>> Yes.
>> Or or or or they're not with it.
>> I think they don't get it. Yes. You
know, like the it's just a classifier
complaint. It's like an ML level concern
while everyone else is having like a
Jeff party [laughter]
>> because it's like holy [ __ ] like we can
do all the things that we wanted to do
and I don't I think if you don't like
get developers it'll be hard to
understand what's really going on. So
100% I agree with that. I do think that
there's like a pretty negative world
painted that I obviously disagree with.
I think it's really comes from this like
um you know mono model Kool-Aid that
everyone believes. I think
>> right one big brain to rule them all.
[laughter]
That's one that's one way to the It
sounds much more ominous.
>> That's what people hear.
>> Yeah, for sure. That's what people
That's what people hear. Yeah.
>> But you know, like will that one is that
one brain really on the path to rule us
all? Like we have not automated really
basic things that I don't think we want
people to be doing, you know, like it
there's lots of really really basic
stuff. And I think that
oh man it it it pains me when the world
is discordant with the reality and like
part of the pain is you know on the
where the [ __ ] is all the automation
like how can we have AI be so freaking
smart and
>> like there's so much so much financial
incentive to automate stuff like yeah
you could make an excuse for diffusion I
don't buy it at all I shouldn't name
names but like that obviously is not
true part of the problem is like the
discordance with the reality and the
fact that AI has like so much potential
is what made it really tragic for me
that we had not released this. So now
it's a now it's like a little bit of a
party for me. But like I was afraid of
>> all dev users are like
>> there's the happy AI the people on Jev
and then there's the morose AI the
people who are not. It's it's really uh
it's quite a kind of fascinating
dichotomy. It's it is really well I give
you and and to your automation point. I
had a funny conversation this morning
with David George who runs our growth
fund because we're talking about the new
tools. I was like have you tried the
Muse thing? He's like oh it's awesome. I
was like what'd you do with it? He said,
"I finally canceled my New York Times
subscription." [laughter]
And I was like,
"That that is hard to do." [laughter]
>> But yeah, you know, it's a kind of a
it's a very tip of the iceberg of the
things that are horrible things to do
that that we need to automate. I think
that if we were going to be really
intellectually honest and we really
aiming for the north star of automation,
we cannot fall into the same
anti-atterns that AI has fallen into
which is really um focusing on outliers
and demos, right? Like a lot of people
ask me like what are your favorite use
cases and I'm like I'm not sure if they
work. I want them to work in the
background such that like someone would
trust that to run and not page them and
like people can build on top of that too
and like
>> composable composable
>> composable but like other things like
safe right like it's a different type of
safety where like if you want it to
actually like run with resources
associated with it with access to things
you need guarantees for that or like at
least statistical guarantees and um
>> so it doesn't go rogue breaking
[laughter] face that type of thing
>> well I I don't think our models will be
doing anytime soon unless somebody like
does the software to do that which would
be very cool flex very cool flex I
should figure out how to give credits
for that but um but not in a way that
we're not responsible
>> right right
>> I'm just curious like how long has this
intuation been percolating cuz I
remember talking to you maybe in was it
>> we did talk about that yeah
>> yeah and like and then like a lot of
these ideas were in your you know you
were talking about data being important
and you're talking about like you want
to focus on the task and like but like
so I I just like you know was this like
did you know that this was going to end
up being a classifier or was this just
an intuition that like there was just
kind of another way to view this entire
kind of AI movement
>> you know so actually a fun story about
that chat in the talk from 2017 I think
my talk was
>> actually in a very similar theme I think
it was called something like AI modular
in theory and flexible in practice which
is very software. So, I'm a little bit
consistent in that. I
>> I think that this really started right
before chat GBT.
>> Um like right when we released these
things, I did not have intuition about
this and honestly I was not even
>> I was very very pleasantly surprised by
the generalization capabilities of RHF.
>> When is this?
>> Must be end of 2021 like a
>> fourth quarter of 2021. [snorts] um like
we were it was really really general
like if you read the paper it's unlike
other papers that are like trying to
prove their point. It was us actually
you know scientific methodish trying to
disprove like is it cheating and uh
>> you know my favorite query was why is it
important to eat socks before
meditating? We made sure that was not on
the internet beforehand and like the
models were able to like make plausible
humanl looking answers for this and that
to us in the team was the thing that
clicked like this is not cheating which
you should always be afraid of cheating
in ML and
>> then what really got me burnt was I we
released it um you know we did a
>> you know I'm obviously a big
capabilities guy I did a lot to release
that model I I really thought that that
model had like a decent chance of being
AGI and when it didn't that was like
when my whole world came crashing down
and I was like why?
>> Oh so you were kind of on the other
train for a bit which like the crazy
train or
>> well no I'm just like under RL
generalizes like maybe we have AGI like
>> RHF generalizes pretty well. RLVR is the
thing that doesn't generalize as well
from what I've seen. Um and
AGI in to
>> well I I was just saying more I mean
like you know you were beh in chat GPT
you were behind like these early GPTs
that was a very different goal which is
like creating a chatbot that will talk
to the human being was not a
programmer's tool etc. So I'm just
wondering like
>> oh well actually early early like 2020
um openai when we talked about AGI
people used to describe it as Ilia and
every if statement. Um, so it's not it's
kind of like but like is that like part
we were talking about open AAI culture
part of it is that it's like
intentionally vague so it's a wide like
tent so that everyone can be inside of
it but like I am not
>> for nuanced reasons I don't think we are
on the path of RSI and I still don't
think we're in the path of RSI and I did
then I do think that what OpenAI defined
as AGI is extremely doable automating
most of the world's economically
valuable
actually sounds
>> like uh
>> oh man I don't like there's a there's a
lot of work out there a lot of it is
very wrote and simple and like by volume
in order to be able to like outsource
work you need like simple instructions
that like basic people can do and as far
as I can tell the intelligence of that
has been available in the models for
like quite a while now and
>> like my oh man you know chip on my
shoulder is like why is this not
available and and then the the and then
since RHF the AI industry just like kind
of bifurcated into gigantic overpromise
underdeliver I think GPT3 was actually
quite calibrated back in that day but
because humans evaluate how good the
models are it looks really good cuz they
are the judge but we've been optimizing
that judge instead of the automation
part and that has been the missing thing
so I would say it was really really then
that it like hit me you know like why is
this thing not more useful
>> and so you think that the measure that
we should have is to what extent Can you
automate actual productive tasks? Is
that the
>> the over when you say overpromise and
underdel? That's the dimension in
particular you're talking to. The
ability to automate tasks.
>> I like I think in my heart it's like
cool sci-fi. Um you know and I think
that I think that that is the canary in
the coal mine for cool sci-fi. Like, are
you really telling me that we like math
is solved or like even like 2 years ago
GPQA that Google proof question
answering is solved, but we still can't
handle a drive-thru, right? Like it's
[laughter] it's it's it's a very hard
thing to hold in your head at once and I
think a lot of people don't have good
answers to that.
>> Yeah. Can I can I just test one thing
which which may which may not make sense
but I want I mean I mean isn't there an
argument though that like
>> the the the real the distribution of the
real world is is is different than the
digital world right it's heavy tailed
there's a lot of exceptions we don't
have all the data and I mean it couldn't
it be the case that the reason we're not
doing productive stuff in the real world
is just like we're not we don't have the
data for that distribution we're not
training on that distribution and this
is why it's just been basically
relegated to like these is lower
dimensional manifolds like whatever math
or code or
>> um I don't entirely buy the data
argument in my opinion. Um I do believe
that there's a a long tail for sure like
that that would be kind of crazy to deny
and I don't think that in my like canary
in the coal mine situation we need to
automate that long tail. Like I think
that I think we need to be incredibly
pragmatic on everything and like
building reliable software is always an
investment, right? Like it like you know
what were the three great virtues of a
programmer? Laziness to not to do it
again, hubris. And
>> there was a third one.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, I remember this is from
the Pearl days. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. There there was a third one.
>> Very well. Yeah. I I wish I wish I could
remember it, but like it's about like
the laziness to like spend, you know,
like 10 hours to do like the five minute
task instantly and to never have to do
it again. Like it only make like it
should be an ROI decision for people who
like automate stuff. Like I would just
like it to be automatable and I think
that people will just make like new
kinds of work, hence the Jev in jeans,
new kinds of work once that stuff is
doable. But uh like as like a a
benchmark, I feel like it's useful to
see can we actually automate the stuff
that it really really looks like AI
should be able to automate. Open AAI has
been trying to automate customer service
since 2020, you know, like and it it
it's you know like it's not
>> which is pretty amazing. [laughter]
>> It's it's wild, you know. It's wild.
Well, and then inside I mean inside
companies um
>> there's very little that's automated
right now like and the projects haven't
worked
>> other than programming has worked
amazing.
>> Can you can you maybe classify the types
of problems you think that are easier to
automate now because it it was kind of
interesting. So we've actually looked at
support before the current generative
wave and it was interesting. you'd meet
a company and the company would say um
we uh we answer 95% of all like you know
like help desk calls and like that is so
many
>> but then you actually look at the data
>> and you realize it's all password resets
>> and then like but if you did it by like
the uniqueness it was only something
like 50% or so so it just feels like
when you're dealing with humans and
natural systems like there's just kind
of this very kind of
>> you know like long tale of exceptions
and so to what extent did like I every
but probably every hour I have somebody
ping me and like I'm using Jeb for this
new use case. I'm like I had no idea you
know like you know and so like to what
extent did you even predict like the
broad range of use case for it like did
you assume that was going to happen and
have you been surprised by that or
>> extremely surprised did not assume it
would happen. Uh this launch was
>> like not something like if anyone
expected this they are probably insane.
Um right like it is I I don't think
someone could expect a chat GPT for
developers cuz chat GPT was for you know
like you know the normal users and
>> it's weird. I actually don't even know
what percentage of the people who are
part of the JF party are developers
themselves. I can't imagine
non-developers using it. I don't know
how they would use it. Um but even my
non-developer friends are just like part
of the party and Twitter and memeing and
everything like that. So, number one,
phenomenal. Number two, um this will be
hard to convey in this short message
because like it's been like blood,
sweat, and tears for years now. Like the
amount I care about reliability is um
it's it's a lot. Like reliability is
what this thing is. If you don't
understand that, it'll be very hard to
make like a copycat that's benchmaxed.
Like it's
>> I feel like every nine of reliability is
going to be so valuable for everyone
even if it's not the most valuable thing
market capwise because it will just
enable new applications and like we are
fighting for like all sorts of like
weird nines of reliability that like we
don't even fully understand because we
are just like you know like really
getting this like electric motor of AI
of intelligence like into people's like
workstations and they can figure out
what to do with it. What does
reliability mean in this context? Is
this is this like availability of the
model or is it like I call the model and
it returns the same thing or like how do
I think about reliability?
>> Yeah. So
>> for something that's inherently kind of
stoastic.
>> So uh not so much the former thing and
the second thing is closer like I would
describe the first thing as kind of like
uptime or SLAs's. The second thing I
would maybe call closer to determinism.
The something thirdly I would consider
more like robustness. So robustness I
would kind of describe as um similar
intelligence every time.
>> Oh, interesting.
>> Yeah. So like not exactly determinism
because I think determinism it's useful
for unit tests but not real systems.
Think about like if you add a UU ID to a
prompt, it should be the same cuz it's
the same functionally but it's not
exactly deterministic. I think that
there's a another layer of it that I
don't really know what it's called yet.
Like maybe this is what I would call
like some form of intelligence which is
it doesn't have to be the similar
function every time but it needs to be
smart every time you know like if you
were in that situation would this be an
understandable thing for a human to
think because a developer can program
around that and actually to me the
highest honor of reliability will be to
get to the point where people can
program against Jev without making
example queries like when you just trust
it you'll be in like peraflow state
And that's where
I think it's unrealist
feel free like if if it's too weird just
feel free but um it occurs to me that
actually the value of things like coding
agents goes down if you have a primitive
like this in a way which is like you
could be like you know whatever some you
know codeex builds all the software for
me but it doesn't actually use Jev and
so like the software itself it creates
is somewhat limited or you can be like
okay I as a human being I will write the
software without using a coding agent
but I've got this very generalized
primitive that makes writing software
easier. So like do you feel like see a
future where it's like the coding agents
using Jev and then you're telling the
coding agents and then do you have like
redundancy or do you feel it's like
humans hip?
>> This is more of like a coding agent
question than it is a Jev question. Oh
yeah. So my vibe is that um I'm not in
the coding minds as much as I'd like to
be. So you are you two might be in there
more than I am which is sad but my
experience is that they are really good
at syntax and really
>> they're bad at semantics.
>> Um
I would say incredibly bad at
architecture.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and so like to me architecture is
like the most human creative part of
software. So I love using coding agents.
I think that uh Jev is almost certainly
not in distribution. that would be
spooky if they trained on our user data.
Um, so it's probably not. Um, but uh I
think that when it is in distribution, I
I see no problem with like having it do
the syntax. And the thing with
architecture is that maybe the models
are actually like not just crap at
architecture, but maybe they're 50th
percentile architecture. And if you
don't know anything about architecture,
it would be fine. So these are all like
gray area tradeoffs in order for you to
navigate. And sometimes speed is the the
knob for your company or project to turn
like you're willing to do a 50th like a
50th percentile architecture instead of
a 60th because you want to move faster
and have like codeex work overnight or
something like that. Right.
>> Yeah. Actually kind of along those lines
one of the interesting things or
phenomenons in the market already is
that you know when the coding agents
came out it was the SAS apocalypse and
all their values dropped through the
floor and then when Jev came out every
SAS company is like this is the greatest
thing ever. So explain that.
>> I I don't know what else to say, right?
Like I I think it's like quite natural.
Like in the SAS apocalypse story, um the
the story that I feel like has panned
out really poorly is that software is
very cheap and perhaps easy to
replicate, which I think I could I could
believe the former. I could not believe
the latter because a lot of the stuff
happens beneath the hood. Um I'm maybe
overly a software fanboy here. All of
us.
>> Okay. Okay. Okay. Um I didn't know where
might be the coding.
>> We have a lot of legacy around that
100%.
>> Yeah. So I don't think that really
panned out. So SAS seems like maybe the
markets don't agree, but like I think
SAS is providing the same value it used
to. Maybe the markets are just scared.
Um but I think that SAS will be one of
the largest winners of like the whole AI
game. And I want to like work really
really well with like all the biggest
most boring most like in the know of
user problem SAS companies because I
think that they are the best positioned
to know what workflows to automate what
do people need like that's what their
bread and butter is and to spend the big
like you know software is always a capex
investment and but like you spend it
ahead of time in order to make this
experience even better that gets you
know like distributed to all of that
mass of users. So, I think that it's
going to be I'm I I'm not going to
forecast anything about the financial
markets, but I think for as far as like
a capabilities games goes, it's going to
be like an inverse apocalypse. And I am
so jazzed about it. We I should make a
name.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That Yeah, that that should
have a name.
>> SAS Palooa.
>> Oh, [laughter]
that sounds a little too fun.
>> Well, all the SAS applications are going
to all of a sudden get like dramatically
more useful. And by the way, you know,
the the the kind of uh capital
investment like so much of a of a SAS
company's capital investment is like
actually getting to all the customers.
And so if you've gotten to all the
customers and then you make, you know,
not just put a chatbot on your SAS
product, but actually make the software
like way way better, um that's a hell of
a thing. I don't know if this is a
realistic dream or not, but I think that
there's a world where like the
multi-choice choice forms just
disappear, you know, like I I feel like
they are like they are always like
something mapping natural language that
usually the software already has into
like a Jeike output and I think
>> it's literally it's literally from the
80s. It's like it's called we used to
call it 4GS. Do you remember
>> fourth generation language? Actually,
also I think this is from the 80s. This
might be an insult. I was more than um
the like I think that do what I mean is
going to like be taken to the absolute
next level. If I could shout out one Jev
application, I don't know if it's
reliable, so I can't promise anything,
but it was so freaking cool. Someone was
using like a voice to control your
computer and it was basically constantly
making decisions on like is this a
command or is it inserting text? Where's
inserting text? Like like that sounds so
unbelievably cool. Like like I feel like
interfaces could like just completely
change and maybe we're going to have to
make it like cheaper and faster, you
know?
>> Yeah. Then you're at Star Trek.
[laughter]
>> Well,
you know, there's there's just such a
profound intuition here, which is um um
you know, if if you use AI today to
generate software, right? you're still
creating the the same software that you
did before, but if you actually look at
like the average PR for a large company,
it's like 10 lines, right? Seriously.
Nove.
We actually did the study. So, it's like
10 lines. So, like you're automating 10
lines. And by the way, those 10 lines
are are like, you know, part of a
learning from a customer or something.
So, like you're you've kind of optimized
something that's actually pretty
minimal. Um, but what it doesn't do is
provide new capabilities to the
software, right? It's kind of automating
this thing which in the limit ends up
being relatively minor. And now like
there's actually a new capability and so
like it could just be the case that just
software just actually gets better.
Yeah. And and by the way it didn't even
before Jeff like just it didn't even
occur to me that like it doesn't matter
how much you know AI coding agents you
use the software actually isn't getting
better. Maybe you're writing it faster.
It's like arguably getting worse just
because like there's less oversight. So
I think this is
>> well and and often more insecure.
>> Yeah. For sure. For sure. But you're but
you're actually now can make an argument
like like like apps will have new
functionalities as a result of this
because there is this new primitive that
you're providing that I mean like in in
a way like it speaks natural languages
and it can reason but it marries that to
a state machine.
I if people take that as a takeaway that
would be like the greatest compliment
ever to what we are doing like I
actually feel like it's almost too grand
of a vision to expand beyond the three
logic gates that we have into like you
know it our types are kind of like one
of the same logic gate but like one
that's like a little brain in there like
that would be the greatest compliment to
like the the type safe legacy cuz like
that is that's a very non-trivial huge
thing for the world. Um, I'm not going
to like overpromise underdel that, but I
will fight for that.
>> Yeah. I mean, listen, I mean, there's I
think pretty open questions to what like
how deep can this get as far as like
like really serious stuff like state
consistency or durability or like real
systems level stuff where you actually
need to like provide strong guarantees.
And so 100% this will change things like
whatever analyzing logs, analyzing
emails, providing a UI, talking to the
human like that for sure. But like you
know you could argue that over time this
becomes like a smart database like you
know and so
>> and also
>> air traffic control system
>> which we really need.
>> True true
>> a little scary like I think automate the
easy work before the hard work is always
my philosophy but I also think there's
going to be like an entire era of
probabilistic programming that's opened
up like my
>> by the way you know there's a huge
history of proistic program that
basically died in like the 70s or I'm
familiar with it. I I I actually think
it's going to be like with the same like
you could also call Jeb like neuros.
>> So your co your co-founder Eric came
from that background. He was telling me
kind of basian.
>> Oh yes yes yes. He did a lot of biology
stuff that goes up and down but like
what I mean is a more
>> I'm not a fan my brand is pragmatism.
Incredible pragmatism. I'm not a fan of
like biologically inspired stuff um at
all.
>> This never worked. Have you ever noticed
that? I mean I I think it's never
worked. It's useful to motivate crazy
people to work on things for decades
until it works and then they refine it
into like the engineering
>> the story of AI neural nets for sure.
>> Yes. But like you know a lot of the
stories about how it worked were not
accurate right so like the hierarchical
features of applications really did end
up working cuz like otherwise resets
wouldn't have worked. longer story. Um,
I I do think that it opens up like like
from a systems perspective. I'm not
excited about this part cuz it's really
I'm excited for the world, not about me
programming this cuz it sounds like
really complicated. But I think that as
we have like lots of intelligence at
lots of uh like different cost and speed
trade-offs, the super systemsy types
will be be making trade-offs at like you
know like dev is going to be like a
thousand times too smart for them. They
just want like an approximate link to
have an approximate guess to like
optimistically route here and there.
It's gonna be like so crazy the the type
of stuff that's available in the extreme
systems
>> and the and the good news is we get to
like rebuild systems again which is
great right we have a new no seriously
we have a new primitive it's kind of a
new way think about doing software like
I mean we did listen we did this with
the internet you we did this main frame
to client server I mean we do this
periodically and and by the way just
because of the um cyber security issues
we probably have to rebuild almost all
the systems uh to to just make them
safe. I I would think
>> I think it's pretty clear that there
like there's not no
>> or at least the critical the the
critical infrastructure for sure.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Do you do you think about
this more in terms of like apps, SAS,
analytics or
more in terms of like systems
foundations or all the above
>> for what I would think of or how
>> just general application for this when
you think about like like you're working
on Jev and like and you kind of envision
that people are adapting it like how you
know like do maybe do you even have an
opinion? I have a little bit and it's
so the way I think of it is a little
like uh like deep into like the TCP
guts, you know, like UDP TCP, you know,
like it's unreliable, too reliable,
>> speaking my language.
>> Exactly. And like [laughter] I I so like
when I think of AI no I mean like when I
think of AI and this is why I care about
intelligence per dollar to be clear when
I think and how I got to this conclusion
I work backwards from AI based economic
revolution AI everywhere know sci-fi and
everything like all the software has AI
all over the place and I asked myself
the question what percentage of the
calls to AI imagine it's like a function
which what percentage are like for human
consumption where you need style and
everything and yeah and it's going to be
like many nines and actually from that
same question, how many will be at the
first layer versus like deep in the
guts, right? And I think that it's going
to be many nines in the guts, but it
will start at the first layer. But like
we need to if you don't aim for the
guts, right? That sounds weird.
[laughter] If you don't aim for the
guts, you it's it's going to take you a
while to get there, right? I think
people don't understand to what extent
like AI was kind of shipped in the night
with software. Like even if you try to
embed AI in software, it kind of like
didn't behave, right? because software
doesn't really take natural languages
and you like do all this weird stuff
like you stick in the prompt like here's
the JSON output that you want and here's
the schema and it would never listen to
it and so and so what you ended up doing
is just taking the output and giving it
to a human you're like the hell with it
right or another LM that is what a while
loop is like the agent while loop right
so it's like it's like from first
principles it needs to be human in the
loop which is chat
>> or an agent which is the while loop
because like the natural language needs
to be fed back into another
>> and I will say I I have watched this h
there was almost like this kind of like
five stages of grief that like
[laughter] you know people would pick up
AI and like I'm going to use this you
know within my software right and then
you know and then it would like go with
like you know whatever denial like try
to make it work and like anger then they
go to acceptance which is like okay
never mind I'm just going to give this
to another LM to a human being so it's
been very ships in the night I think
this is the first time I have seen it's
almost like actually you can take an LLM
you can take AI and you can actually map
it to like like a state machine and you
can do that productively
And I hope so. I will not want to
overpromise underdeliver as well. Like I
don't know if it's ready for all the
applications that have been
overpromised. I really really want it to
and my team will fight for that
obviously. Like we
>> really really care about reliability. We
could have released so much sooner. I
don't think people realize that and I
don't think that honestly I don't think
that they will based on what I see off
the Twitter discussion. I think it's
people will never get it, but like it'll
just have like that good vibe of like,
oh, I can trust this. So,
>> it's the anti- frustration machine.
[laughter]
[gasps]
>> It's it's a I hope so. I hope do what I
mean, right? Like to me that is about
like smoothness in the world, like
having everything like just move more
smoothly together and interlink like a
gears. I actually have my whole like AI
utopia on like different axes that I
really really want and like do what I
mean is a huge part of this, you know,
like imagine if all technology just did
what you mean.
>> That is like that's not sci-fi. Look how
smart AI is, right?
>> Yeah. No, it's a it's amazing. And and
maybe that's the thought to close on.
Oh,
>> do what I mean.
>> Yeah. I love it.
>> Thank you, Dio. This has been a great
conversation. Really enjoyed it.